PRIMARY EXPERIENCE

Digital Designer Finn Partners (finnpartners.com), New York City

2011-present

Translated clients' functional and visual needs into pixel-perfect designs using Fireworks, Illustrator, and Photoshop Created site maps, functionality documents, final designs and other deliverables for our team's developer Coded unique interactive visualizations for the web using Javascript and JQuery and RaphaeUS libraries Brainstormed and fleshed out ideas for new digital initiative to pitch to clients including microsites, Facebook Apps Juggled multiple deadlines, projects, and bosses. On call whenever, but the team-spirit made it worth it computer applications used: Photoshop Illustrator Fireworks Excel Word

Research Intern Talking Points Memo (talkingpointsmemo.com), New York City

winter 2010-2011

Maintained web articles, edited photography, and worked with web developer on interactive features Illustrator Photoshop Excel Word

Web and Media Intern St. Louis Beacon Newspaper (stlbeacon.org), St. Louis MO

summer 2010

Collaborated with editors and reporters to design tailored data visualizations for variety of news stories

Illustrator Photoshop Premier InDesign Excel Word**

Designer Shanghai Repertory Theater, Shanghai China

2009 - 2011

Designed postcards, invitations, posters, backdrops, and anything else flat for theater companies

Illustrator Photoshop InDesign

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Freelance Technology Writer Talking Points Memo (talkingpointsmemo.com), New York City

Wrote articles about technology and science with the potential to change industry and politics

Program Assistant Carleton College Political Economy Seminar, Europe

spring 2011

"Project Manager" for off-campus study program. 25 students, three countries, ten months, one professor.

Educational Advisor Taurus Education, Shanghai, China

2009 - 2010

Taught classes on the basics of English grammar, essay writing classes, and American culture classes

Executive Editor The *Carl*, Carleton's biweekly arts and literature publication, Northfield MN QuarkXpress. Photoshop 7. Old computers constantly breaking.

2006 - 2009

EDUCATION

School for Visual Arts Manhattan NY Continuing Education

2012

Currently enrolled in advanced web languages class for designers. PHP, JQuery, and MYSQL primary emphasis.

Carleton College Northfield MN

2005 - 2009

Developed strong writing and communication skills; teamwork and collaboration emphasized in all classes Performed original political science research on the European Union in the Netherlands, Paris, and Brussels

PARTIAL CLIENT LIST

Stubhub.com

ecommerce

data visualization

Hotels.com

ecommerce

web design & data viz

Dan Rather

author

web design

3LM

Android security

Web Design

Hyundai USA

corporate social responsability
Web Design

Blue Cross Blue Shield of Michigan

Healthcare

International Council of Shopping Centers

Issues/Lobbying

SKILLS AND QUALIFICATIONS

Software Mastery

Adobe Photoshop CS5 Adobe InDesign CS5 Adobe Illustrator CS5 Adobe Fireworks CS5 HTML/CSS/JQuery

Software Proficiency

PHP

Want to Learn

Ruby Python Cinema 4d

EMPLOYMENT LOCATIONS



St. Louis, Missouri Northfield, Minnesota Shanghai, China Maastrich, Netherlands Brooklyn, New York